Justin Blalock

Full-Stack Software Engineer

📧 justin.m.blalock@gmail.com | 📱 936.827.4487 | 🏠 justinblalock.dev | 🐱 github.com/jmblalock



Projects

Wayfarer

Interactive traveling blog. Users can post articles and learn from other users' experiences and comments. Wayfarer has an internal API hosting 60+ destinations. Includes authentication and full CRUD on posts. Built with Python, Django and a PostgreSQL relational database.

Zip Code Collective

Online shopping experience with a focus on supporting local businesses. Zip Code Collective includes authentication, role-based permissions, password reset emails, image upload and credit card charging via Stripe API. Built with JavaScript React, Next.js, KeystoneJS (headless CMS), GraphQL, Typescript and a NoSQL MongoDB database.

justinblalock.dev

Personal website and portfolio. Built with Next.js, React, designed with TailwindCSS and hosted on Ubuntu running NginX on DigitalOcean.

Experience

Enterprise Account Executive @ Everbrige

April 2019 - Present // Austin, TX

- * Responsible for managing the business relationship with Everbridge's larger customers, up to \$10,000M in annual revenue
- Develops and executes sales strategies and tactics to generate pipeline, drive sales opportunities and deliver repeatable and predictable bookings
- ❖ Identifies net new leads that fit within ideal client profiles to market the Everbridge's products and services that will meet potential client's needs

Account Executive @ Box

June 2017 - Mar 2019 // Austin, TX

- Managed the business relationship with Box's commercial customers and was responsible for generating sales of Box's cloud software-as-a-service (SaaS), platform-as-a-service (PaaS) as well as consulting services.
- ❖ Helped build a new application from scratch utilizing an internal alpha SDK

EDUCATION

General Assembly, Austin, TX - Software Engineering Immersive

SEPT 2020 - DEC 2020

Baylor University, Waco, TX — Bachelor of Business Administration - BBA

Skills

Programming Languages

- lavaScript (ES6+)
- HTML
- CSS
- **Typescript**
- GraphQL
- Python

Frameworks & Libraries

- React
- TailwindCSS
- Jest
- Next.is
- Gatsby
- Vue.js
- Node.js
- **Express**
- KeystoneJS
- **j**Query

Tools & Platforms

- **VSCode**
- Atom
- Git
- GitHub
- Webpack
- Heroku
- Netlify
- Postman
- Docker
- Digital Ocean
- Ubuntu
- NginX

Database

- MongoDB
- PostgreSQL
- MySQL

Design

- Figma
- balsamiq